Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Latin American Exhibition Catalogs and Visual Resources
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Latin American exhibition catalogs and visual resources
1929-2008
1990-2008
ART 25
Yale University Arts Library
2.25
(4 boxes)
The collection contains published exhibition catalogs from various Latin American countries and mounted reproductions of individual artworks by Latin American artists.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Librarian for Latin American Studies, Jana Krentz, in January 2014. Materials may have originated from the Yale Department of Spanish and Portuguese.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains published exhibition catalogs from various Latin American countries and mounted reproductions of individual artworks by Latin American and Spanish artists. The collection also includes a few original watercolors.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Published Works, 1976-2008. II. Reproductions, 1929-1991. III. Original Artwork, 1996.
Art, Latin American; Exhibition catalogs
- Published Works, 1976-2008; Series I; 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes a variety of exhibition catalogs, auction catalogs, brochures, pamphlets, and other art-related ephemera, primarily published in Brazil.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically by year of publication.
  - Santeiros Imaginários, 1976; 1 (Box 1)
  - Paulo Chaves, Março 1979, 1 (Box 1)
  - Antonio Vitor (Exposição dedicada à Francesc Domingo), Maio 1979, 1 (Box 1)
  - Carlos Araujo, Pinturas — dezembro 1979, 1 (Box 1)
  - Tikashi Fukushima [Galeria de Arte André], 1985; 2 (Box 1)
  - Jorge Mori, Quarenta Anos de Pintura, 1985; 1 (Box 1)
  - Antonio Augusto Marx [Galeria de Arte André], 1986; 1 (Box 1)
  - Helenos, Iconografia da Brasilândia, 1986; 1 (Box 1)
  - Daniel Carranza [Galeria de Arte André], 1986; 1 (Box 1)
  - Guérati, Paisagem Brasileira, 1986; 2 (Box 1)
  - Satyro Marques [Galeria de Arte André], 1986; 3 (Box 1)
  - Wakabayashi [Realidade Galeria de Arte], 1987; 1 (Box 1)
  - Azulejos Portugueses Séculos XVII a XX, 1987; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pennacchi, Sessenta Anos de Pintura, 1987; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sun Chia Chin, 1987; 1 (Box 1)
  - Adriana Rocha [Sadalla Galeria de Arte], 1989; 1 (Box 1)
  - A Via Seca, Ocidente-Oriente em sete encontros, 1990; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pancetti, Um Pintor Pintor, 1997; 1 (Box 1)
  - Destaques da Coleção Unibanco, 1998; 1 (Box 1)
  - Obras sobre papel, Do Modernismo à Abstração, 1999; 1 (Box 1)
  - Macaparana, Obras Recentes, 2000; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mário Zavagli, Paisagens Mineiras, 2001; 1 (Box 1)
  - Samson Flexor, 2002; 1 (Box 1)
  - Gilce Velasco, Rosamundi, 2002; 1 (Box 1)
  - Companhia das Artes, 2003; 1 (Box 1)
  - Impressões Digitais: Esculturas de Valdir Rocha, 2004; 1 (Box 1)
  - Midrash, Yara Martins, 2004; 1 (Box 1)
  - Antonio Titto, Manifestação, 2004; 1 (Box 1)
  - Companhia das Artes, 2004; 1 (Box 1)
  - Construtivos e Cinéticos, 2004; 1 (Box 1)
  - Paulo Carapunarlo, 2004; 2 (Box 1)
  - O Brasil de Marc Ferrez, Fotografias do Acervo do Instituto Moreira Salles, 2006; 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Anish Kapoor, Ascension [Centro Cultural Banco do Brasil], 2007; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Gregório Gruber, Pinturas, 2007; 2 (Box 1)
  - Ivald Granato, o Gesto e a Arte, 2007; 2 (Box 1)
  - A Cidade Iluminada de Newton Mesquita, 2007; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pitágoras, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Confissão de um Reitor Lalau ao Rabinzin da Gravata, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Braudel Papers, No. 42, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Segall Realista, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Ruptura Frente Ressonâncias, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pagina 22, No. 19, 2008; 2 (Box 1)
  - Stephen Henriques, Passagens, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Escrituras & Bordaduras, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - André Cencin, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Garcia Arte, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Conceição Queiroz, Stella Bianco, Sylvia Soares: Pinturas e Desenhos, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mario Cravo Neto, a Flecha em Repouso, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mundo Fiat, No. 91, 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sizudo Lorca [Livraria Cultura], 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - O Novo Expressionismo: Cabral, Perelman, Ayoub, 2008; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Margarita Farré [Esculturas], 2008; 1 (Box 1)
  - Antonio Ocelio de Sá, undated; 3 (Box 1)
  - Lucia Helena, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sexta Fuego [Boca Club postcard], undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - O Instituto Ricardo Brennand e o Resgate do Brasil Holandês, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Jadel Gregório, A trajetória de um atleta, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Galeria Arte Aplicada [business card], undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Racismo: se você não fala, quem vai falar?, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - O Sindicato do Crime: PCC e outros Grupos, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - SENAI: Automobilística Eletroeletrônica, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Compendio de la Historia de la Pintura en Venezuela, undated; 1 bound volume, including 35 mm slides (Box 1)
  - A Biblia: Illustrada por Carlos Araujo, 1998; 1 (Box 2)
- Reproductions, 1929-1991; Series II; 2
  This series includes reproductions of individual artworks or other designs, such as magazine covers, mounted on either card stock or foam core.
  Arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - Araujo, Carlos, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Ballester, José Manuel, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Berrvezo, Josep, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Busca, Ángel, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Costa, Roca D., undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Dias, Cícero, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Díaz, Carlos, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Estes, Richard, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Feduchi, Leticia, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Franco, Siron, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Goytisolo, Gonzalo, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Häsler, Alejandro, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Häsler, Rudolf, undated; 5 (Box 2)
  - Ivonaldo, undated; 17 (Box 2)
  - Lai, Sok-Kan, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Lanza, Adrià, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Longas, Joan, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Marsans, Luis, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Marsans, Luis & Raimon Sunyer, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Mateo, Raül, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Meyerhoff, Pedro Moreno, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Mora, Joan, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Moya, Andrés, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Nazario, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Padilla, Humberto, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Palazzi, Marcos, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Pina, Adrià & Xavier Visa, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Quijano, Nick, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Realismo en Cataluña, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Ricart, Anna, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Roca-Sastre, Josep, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Rodríguez, Efraïm, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Romero, César, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Rubió, Guillem, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Sacilotto, Luiz, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Santana, Enrique Romero, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Santilari, Josep, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Santilari, Pere, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Santilari, Josep & Pere, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Sardà, Jordi, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Segú, Josep, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Serra de Rivera, Xavier, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Steen, Ricardo van, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Sunyer, Raimon, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Taraborelli, Raquel, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Toledo, Amélia, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Tusquets, Óscar, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Vaquero, Julio, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Vidal, Albert, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified, undated; 1 (Box 2)
    - A Arte do Comércio: Sao Paulo 1900-1930, [1988]; 23 (Box 3)
    - [Careta: Um cruzeiro em todo o Brasil, No. 2.208], [1950]; 1 (Box 3)
    - Carnaval by Claudio Edinger, [1991]; 28 (Box 4)
    - [Fon Fon], undated; 1 (Box 3)
    - [Lady], 1925; 1 (Box 3)
    - [Lily-of-the-Nile], undated; 1 (Box 3)
    - [Maps], undated; 3 (Box 4)
    - [New Year's 1947-1948], 1 (Box 3)
    - [ Para Todos No. 529], [1929]; 1 (Box 3)
    - [ Para Todos No. 562], [1929]; 1 (Box 3)
    - [ Para Todos No. 564], [1929]; 1 (Box 3)
    - [ Para Todos No. 601], [1930]; 1 (Box 3)
- Original Artwork, 1996; Series III; 1
  This series contains original watercolors and a Marilyn Monroe-inspired game.
  - [Marilyn Monroe Game, São Paulo, 1996], 1 (Box 3)
  - Watercolors, undated; Pedroso, Angelica; 6 (Box 4)
  - Watercolors [Birds, Fish, and Gems], undated; 3 (Box 4)